(Although sensory experience may of course be involved).
It is believed that the sensations are too unreliable to constitute knowledge,
A reasoning that is well exemplified by René Descartes and his systematic doubt.
What Kant is trying to find is the limit of human knowledge.
His reasoning can be seen as an attempt to preserve the best out both empirism and rationalism,
While taking into account the criticism they directed at each other.
This is a theory of knowledge often called critical or transcendental idealism.
According to Kant, one must distinguish between two kinds of knowledge: experience knowledge and reasonable knowledge.
Experience knowledge (or empirical knowledge) is something whose truth
We cannot know without reference to experience.
An example of this is that Paris is the capital of France.